Finding Aid for James J. Blanchard Papers, 1982-2002
Bentley Historical Library
- Press Office, 1982-1991
  - Photographs, 1983-1990
    - General (A to Z), 1983-1990
      - Detroit Crime Lab, November 9, 1987 (Box 189)
      - Detroit Medical Center (Box 189)
      - Detroit Science Center (Superheroes Event), February 1990 (Box 189)
      - Detroit Tiger Games (Box 189)
      - Downriver Community Conference (Box 189)
      - Economic Club of Detroit (Box 189)
      - Economic Development (with Robb) (Box 189)
      - Economic Forum (Southfield), March 30, 1988 (Box 189)
      - Education, 1986-1990
        - College Visits, 3 folders (Box 189)
        - Great Lakes Education Day, May 18, 1989 (Box 189)
        - Head Start (Box 189)
        - Hispanic Education Conference, April 14, 1989 (Box 189)
        - MET Events (Box 189)
        - Michigan Model (Box 189)
        - Schools Tour, February-March 1990 (Box 189)
        - Teacher of the Year (Detroit), May 2, 1986 (Box 189)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 189)
      - Environment Conference, April 1990 (Box 190)
      - Executive Corps, 1983-1985 (Box 190)
      - Fairs/Festivals
        - Ionia Free Fair (Box 190)
        - Michigan State Fair, 1990 (Box 190)
        - Queens and Courts (Box 190)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 190)
      - Filipino-Americans, April 24, 1983 (Box 190)
      - Flood Tour, 1986 (Box 190)
      - Ford Assembly Dedication, July 6, 1988 (Box 190)
      - Fund-raisers, 1985; 3 folders (Box 190)
      - General Motors (Box 190)
      - Girl Scout Troop 7901 (Oakland), August 26, 1990 (Box 190)
      - Governor for a Day (J.P. McCarthy) (Box 190)
      - Governor's Staff (Box 190)
      - Grand Prix, 1987-1989 (Box 190)
      - Great Lakes Governor (Box 190)
      - Ground Breakings, 1984-1988
        - Advanced Polypro Resin, July 16, 1985 (Box 190)
        - Arcadia Creek Commons (Kalamazoo) (Box 190)
        - Detroit Free Press, June 27, 1985 (Box 190)
        - Flat Rock (Mazda), 1985 (Box 190)
        - Ionia Prison, April 30, 1985 (Box 190)
        - J.P. Stevens (Box 190)
        - Leprino, April 29, 1988 (Box 190)
        - Macomb County Jail, November 11, 1985 (Box 190)
        - Michigan State University, 1984-1986 (Box 190)
        - Ogihara, August 29, 1985 (Box 190)
        - Yazaki Corporation (Canton), April 1985 (Box 190)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 190)
      - Hispanic Week, September 15, 1986 (Box 190)
      - Holocaust Memorial Center, September 8, 1989 (Box 190)
      - Huron County Event, 1986 (Box 190)
      - Iacocca-Fraser Economic Development Meeting, May 29, 1986 (Box 190)
      - Japan Center for Michigan Universities (Box 190)
      - Jobs (Commission on Jobs and Economy) (Box 190)
      - Labor Day Bridge Walk, 1983-1988 (Box 190)
      - Lansing Downtown Project, February 17, 1986 (Box 190)
      - Law Enforcement (Detroit) (Box 190)
      - Lieutenant Governor Griffiths (Box 190)
      - Lodge Freeway Opening, October 14, 1987 (Box 190)
      - Lo Jack (Southfield), May 19, 1989 (Box 190)
      - Matteson Lower Huron Park Dedication (Menominee), July 24, 1989 (Box 190)
      - Mazda Corporation (Box 190)
      - Michigan Bell Announcement, June 1, 1990 (Box 190)
      - Michigan Edge, April 2, 1987 (Box 190)
      - Michigan Infrastructure Coalition, 1983-1984 (Box 190)
      - Michigan Home Mortgage (Saginaw) (Box 190)
      - Michigan Municipal League (Box 190)
      - Michigan Press Association, January 27, 1984 (Box 190)
      - Michigan Racing Association, September 1989 (Box 190)
      - Michigan Sheriffs Association (Box 190)
      - Michigan Statehood Stamp (Box 190)
      - Midland Cogeneration Venture (Box 190)
      - Ministers' Reception, circa 1983 (Box 190)
      - Modernizing Mound Road, October 23, 1986 (Box 190)
      - Mondale/Ferraro Campaign, 1983-1984 (Box 190)
      - Moose II, February 7, 1987 (Box 190)
      - Motown Celebration, December 1, 1987 (Box 190)
      - Naisbitt, John (Megatrends) (Box 190)
      - National Center for Manufacturing Science (Box 190)
      - National Governors' Association (Box 190)
      - Neighborhood Builders Alliance, 1988 (Box 190)
      - Nippondenso (Box 190)
      - Nu Vision (Flint), April 16, 1987 (Box 190)
      - Office Meetings (Box 190)
      - Olympians, 1984 (Box 190)
      - Opportunities Industrial Relations Center (Saginaw) (Box 190)
      - Parades, 1985-1990
        - Detroit, Labor Day, 1989 (Box 190)
        - Ferndale (Box 190)
        - Frankenmuth (Box 190)
        - Hamtramck, Labor Day, 1990 (Box 190)
        - Holland Tulip Festival (Box 190)
        - Sterling Heights (Box 190)
        - Wyandotte, July 4, 1988 (Box 190)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 190)
      - Police Officers Association of Michigan, September 23, 1986 (Box 190)
      - Presentations to Blanchard (Box 190)
      - Press Conferences, 1986-1987
        - National Steel Co., April 20, 1987 (Box 190)
        - Steelcase, June 13, 1986 (Box 190)
        - Tax Roll Back, March 4, 1986 (Box 190)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 190)
      - Program to Rebuild Michigan, 1984 (Box 190)
      - Public Speaking (Box 190)
      - Redmond, Mickey, Event (Box 190)
      - Research and Technical Institute, January 1989 (Box 190)
      - Rollcall of Freedom (Mackinac Island), July 14, 1986 (Box 190)
      - Ross Roy Event (Box 190)
      - Safety Belt Law, July 1, 1985 (Box 191)
      - Say No to Drugs (Ferndale) (Box 191)
      - Senior Citizens, 2 folders (Box 191)
      - Sesquicentennial (Box 191)
      - Shoreline Tour, July 1989; 32 folders (Box 191)
        (arranged by city or stop)
      - Solidarity Day III, September 15, 1983 (Box 191)
      - Solvency Day (Detroit), November 8, 1985 (Box 191)
      - Southeast Wayne County Chamber of Commerce (Box 191)
      - State Dinner, 1989 (Box 191)
      - State Helicopter (Box 191)
      - Steinman (Mackinac Bridge Architect) (Box 191)
      - Swearing-In (Box 191)
      - Television Shows, 2 folders (Box 191)
      - 12th Street Missionary Baptist Church (Box 191)
      - Union Visits (and related) (Box 191)
      - Upper Peninsula Events (Box 191)
      - Veterans Events (Box 191)
      - Warren (Box 191)
      - Youth Corps, 1984-1989
        - CCC Reforestation, 1984 (Box 191)
        - Cheboygan Event (Box 191)
        - Detroit Tree Planting, May 5, 1989 (Box 191)
        - Kalamazoo Tree Planting, April 1989 (Box 191)
        - Kent County Tree Planting, April 1989 (Box 191)
        - Muskegon Neighborhood Corps (Box 191)
        - River Rouge Rescue, 1986 (Box 191)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 191)
    - Personal/General oversized photographs
      - Blanchard Formal Portraits, 2 images (Box 245)
      - Blanchard in front of Capitol (Box 245)
      - Blanchard with Gerald Ford (Box 245)
      - Blanchard with Lee Iacocca (Box 245)
      - Blanchard with Michigan Retailers (Box 245)
      - Blanchard Caricature (Box 245)
      - Campaign for Governor, 1982; 7 posters (Box 245)
      - Lee Iacocca paying off Chrysler debt (Box 245)
    - Albums, 1984-1990
      - Michigan Youth Corps, 1984-1986; 5 volumes (Box 192)
      - Michigan Youth Corps, 1984-1986; 2 volumes (Box 193)
      - National Governors' Conference (Box 193)
      - John Henry Event, November 20, 1987 (Box 193)
      - Michigan Water Festival, 1987 (Box 193)
      - Democratic National Convention Platform Committee (Mackinac Island), 1988 (Box 193)
      - "The Road to Lansing" (JJB Campaigning) (Box 193)
  - Audiotapes, 1982-1991
    The audiotapes subseries consists of over 1800 tapes in twenty boxes. These tapes are first arranged according to format (reel-to-reel and cassette), then in a strict chronological order. These audiotapes primarily document Blanchard's public appearances, speeches, press conferences, and press interviews. There are some tapes of other members of the Blanchard team, describing their work or the administration's position on an issue. These audiotapes were viewed as the core collection fulfilling the archival mission of the office, so were preserved in excellent order. Given the high esteem accorded these audiotapes, all identifiable tapes were retained.
    - Reel to Reel, 1982-1984
      - Crim Endorsement of Blanchard, 1982; [9940-SR-1]; 1 audiotape (Audiotapes; 5 inch) (Box 194)
        - [Side 1], 1982 April 16; [9940-SR-1-1]; (Lansing House Speaker Bobby Crim announces his endorsement of Jim Blanchard's campaign for Governor of Michigan. Crim states that he will be an active supporter and campaigner in Blanchard's candidacy.)
      - March 1983-May 1984, 41 audiotapes (reel-to-reel tapes) (Box 194)
        - Michigan News Network China Trip-Gov. Blanchard 4:09 outcue: "and with China", [9940-SR-2]; 1 audiotape (Audiotapes; 5 inch) (Box 194)
          - [Side 1], 1984 May 31; [9940-SR-2-1]; (Governor Blanchard discusses his upcoming trip to China and Japan where he would lead a trade delegation to encourage investment in Michigan and to find foreign markets for Michigan products. Most of the trip would be spent in China and working to lay a foundation for trade with China and to further the sister relationship with the Szechuan Province that had been started by Governor Milliken. Radio Broadcast on Michigan News Network.)
        - Paula Blanchard on Product Promotion Program 3:45, [9940-SR-3]; 1 audiotape (Audiotapes; 5 inch) (Box 194)
          - [Side 1], 1984 May 24; [9940-SR-3-1]; (Governor Blanchard's wife, Paula Blanchard, discusses the Product Promotion Program. It is her hope that the program will help people see Michigan produces more than just cars and the products that are produced are high quality.)
        - Pat Babcock Director of Mental Health on Current Status of Mental Health Programs Time: 4:13, [9940-SR-4]; 1 audiotape (Audiotapes; 5 inch) (Box 194)
          - [Side 1], 1984 May 22; [9940-SR-4-1]; (Director of Mental Health Pat Babcock discusses the current status of Mental Health Programs in an interview from May 22, 1984. In the interview, Babcock discusses the changes that have taken place since 1982 to improve the overall Mental Health Program. Some of these changes include: new accredidation for childrens and adult hospitals, restoring staff levels, new policies and criteria for admissions, and dealings with the chronic mentally ill.)
        - "Executive Update" Excerpts from Senior Power Day Speech 4:11, [9940-SR-5]; 1 audiotape (Audiotapes; 5 inch) (Box 194)
          - [Side 1], 1984 May 17; [9940-SR-5-1]; (An excerpt from Governor Blanchard's "Senior Power Day" Speech given on May 17, 1984. In his speech, Blanchard addresses issues regarding Social Seccurity and rising health care costs. He assures the audience that the state of Michigan will never tax Social Security benefits and that new legislation is proposed to help slow down the rising costs of health care.)
        - Acting Director of Michigan Travel Bureau John Savich on Tourism, [9940-SR-6]; 1 audiotape (Audiotapes; 5 inch) (Box 194)
          - [Side 1; no side 2], 1984 May 14; [9940-SR-6-1]; (John Savich, Acting Director of Michigan Travel Bureau, addresses the importance of tourism in Michigan and the first Governor's Conference on tourism.)
            [Access to this material is restricted to the reading room of the Bentley Historical Library.]
            (Duration: 04:03)
        - Hotlines: Tourism Conference Prelim, HMO Conference, 125th Anniversary of Mental Health, China Briefing, [9940-SR-7]; 1 audiotape (Audiotapes; 5 inch) (Box 194)
          - [Side 1; no side 2], 1984 May 11-25; [9940-SR-7-1]; (Governer's Public Information Line announcements including the first Governor's Conference on tourism, HMO conference, 125th Anniversary of Mental Health ceremony, briefing for governor's visit to China)
            (Duration: 12:11)
        - Governor Blanchard on "Tourism in Michigan", [9940-SR-8]; 1 audiotape (Audiotapes; 5 inch) (Box 194)
          - [Side 1; no side 2], 1984 May 14; [9940-SR-8-1]; (Governor Blanchard addressing tourism in Michigan which includes its economic importance and the state government's effort in tourism.)
            (Duration: 04:10)
        - Helping Small Business in Michigan, Governor Blanchard, Michigan News Network, [9940-SR-9]; 1 audiotape (Audiotapes; 5 inch) (Box 194)
          - [Side 1; no side 2], 1984 May 3; [9940-SR-9-1]; (Governor Blanchard talks about small businesses in Michigan and how the state government is helping them.)
        - Barbara McLeod on Franchise Changes, [9940-SR-10]; 1 audiotape (Audiotapes; 5 inch) (Box 194)
          - [Side 1; no side 2], 1984 April 26; [9940-SR-10-1]; (Barbara McLeod on the upcoming regulatory changes on franchise businesses.)
            (Duration: 04:02)
        - Robert Naftaly on Cost Reduction, [9940-SR-11]; 1 audiotape (Audiotapes; 5 inch) (Box 194)
          - [Side 1; no side 2], 1984 April 19; [9940-SR-11-1]; (Robert Naftaly on the state government's cost reductio efforts.)
            (Duration: 03:56)
        - Health Care Cost Containment, Governor Blanchard, Michigan News Network, [9940-SR-12]; 1 audiotape (Audiotapes; 5 inch) (Box 194)
          - [Side 1; no side 2], 1984 April 12; [9940-SR-12-1]; (Governor Blanchard talks about five areas of the health care cost containment.)
            (Duration: 04:08)
        - James Robinson on "Higher Education Report" Michigan News Network, [9940-SR-13]; 1 audiotape (Audiotapes; 5 inch) (Box 194)
          - [Side 1; no side 2], 1984 April 5; [9940-SR-13-1]; (Former United States Attorney for the Eastern District of Michigan James Robinson discussed the financial state of Michigan's public higher education. He briefly touched upon potential plans for the next 15 years.)
            (Duration: 00:04:11)
        - CCC Bill Signing, [9940-SR-20]; 1 audiotape (Audiotapes; 5 inch) (Box 194)
          - [Part 1], March 7, 1984; [9940-SR-20-1]; (James Blanchard talks discusses the Civilian Conservation Corps.)
            (Duration: 4:14)
        - Republican Control of State Senate-What it means- MNN Taping, [9940-SR-21]; 1 audiotape (Audiotapes; 5 inch) (Box 194)
          - [Part 1], February 23, 1984; [9940-SR-21-1]; (James Blanchard discusses working with republicans and republican control of state senate.)
            (Duration: 00:04:25)
        - Human Services and Budget, [9940-SR-22]; 1 audiotape (Audiotapes; 5 inch) (Box 194)
          - [Part 1], February 9, 1984; [9940-SR-22-1]; (James Blanchard discusses humans services and the budget.)
            (Duration: 00:04:10)
        - Barbara Gentry, Director, Office of Women Business Owners, Mi Dept. of Commerce, [9940-SR-23]; 1 audiotape (Audiotapes; 5 inch) (Box 194)
          - [Part 1], February 7, 1984; [9940-SR-23-1]; (Barbara Gentry discusses the Office of Women Business Owners.)
            (Duration: 00:04:15)
        - Budget MNN Taping, [9940-SR-24]; 1 audiotape (Audiotapes; 5 inch) (Box 194)
          - [Part 1], February 2, 1984; [9940-SR-24-1]; (James Blanchard discusses his proposed budget.)
            (Duration: 00:03:55)
        - Budget Increase for Education and 81 point plan for excellence MNN, [9940-SR-26]; 1 audiotape (Audiotapes; 5 inch) (Box 194)
          - [Part 1], January 20, 1984; [9940-SR-26-1]; (James Blanchard discusses the budget increase for education.)
            (Duration: 04:21)
        - Forest Products Industry, [9940-SR-27]; 1 audiotape (Audiotapes; 5 inch) (Box 194)
          - [Part 1], January 12, 1984; [9940-SR-27-1]; (James Blanchard discusses the forest products industry.)
            (Duration: 00:04:18)
        - Paul Kindinger on AIMS Program, [9940-SR-28]; 1 audiotape (Audiotapes; 5 inch) (Box 194)
          - [Part 1], January 1984; [9940-SR-28-1]; (Paul Kindinger discusses the AIMS Program.)
            (Duration: 00:04:26)
        - Michigan Business Ombudsman, [9940-SR-29]; 1 audiotape (Audiotapes; 5 inch) (Box 194)
          - [Part 1], November 1983; [9940-SR-29-1]; (James Blanchard discusses Michigan Business Ombudsman David Hanes.)
            (Duration: 00:04:12)
        - Environmental Protection; Executive Update, [9940-SR-30]; 1 audiotape (Audiotapes; 5 inch) (Box 194)
          - [Part 1], November 6, 1983; [9940-SR-30-1]; (James Blanchard discusses Environmental Protection on Executive Update.)
            (Duration: 05:51)
      - June 1984-December 1984, 40 audiotapes (reel-to-reel tapes) (Box 195)
      - Undated, 5 audiotapes (reel-to-reel tapes) (Box 195)
      - WKAR Radio/Year End Interview, 1983 December 15; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips (Box 194)
        - [Part 1], [9940-SR-14-1]; (Interview on his experiences on being governor for a year and Michigan's economy.)
      - State of the State Address, 1984 January 18; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips (Box 194)
        - [Part 1], [9940-SR-17-1]; (James J. Blanchard's State of the State Address from 1984.)
    - Cassette Tapes, 1982-1991
      - August 1982-September 1985, 102 audiocassettes (Box 196)
        - Convention speech, [9940-SR-87]; 1 audiocassettes (Audiocassettes) (Box 196)
          - [Side 1], 8/28/1982; [9940-SR-87-1]; (A James Blanchard convention speech.)
            (Duration: 21:11)
          - [Side 2], 8/28/1982; [9940-SR-87-2]; (A James Blanchard convention speech.)
            (Duration: 23:27)
        - State of the State Address, [9940-SR-88]; 1 audiocassettes (Audiocassettes) (Box 196)
          - [Side 1; no side 2], January 1983; [9940-SR-88-1]; (Govenor James Blanchard's first State of the State Address, dubbed from WKAR. In his speech, Govenor Blanchard addresses Michigan's financial crisis and increasing deficit as well as the high unemployment rates. He proposes new executive orders to manage the unemployment rate as well as budget cuts and an increase in income taxes to help overcome the financial crisis and balance the state budget. At the end of the speech WKAR reporters discuss the speech with two analysts.)
        - Governor's news conference: Wall St. trip. Roll back workers' comp rate, [9940-SR-89]; 1 audiocassettes (Audiocassettes) (Box 196)
          - [Side 1; no side 2], 1983; [9940-SR-89-1]; (News conference with Governor Blanchard and the Treasurer of Michigan. Govenor Blanchard discusses his trip to Wall Street and the his plan to rollback worker's comp and unemployment comp. He hopes these rollbacks will decrease the insurance rates for Michigan workers. Governor Blanchard takes questions from the press.)
        - Chamber legislative conference, [9940-SR-90]; 1 audiocassettes (Audiocassettes) (Box 196)
          - [Side 1; no side 2], 5/22/1983; [9940-SR-90-1]; (Michigan Chamber Legislative Conference with Governor Blanchard. Govenor Blanchard discusses his fiscal recovery plan for Michigan and his plans to help save the state from bankruptcy. He also discusses his plans for economic development and his strategies for bringing back jobs.)
        - Side A: FY 1984 budget; Side B: Adrian, [9940-SR-91]; 1 audiocassettes (Audiocassettes) (Box 196)
          - [Side 2; no side 1], 7/5/1983; [9940-SR-91-2]; (Governor Jim Blanchard records a radio spot for a radio station in Adrian.)
            (Duration: 1:05)
        - Detroit News interview, [9940-SR-92]; 1 audiocassettes (Audiocassettes) (Box 196)
          - [Side 1], 12/12/1983; [9940-SR-92-1]; (Governor Blanchard's interview with the Detroit News. In the interview Blanchard reflects on some of the accomplishments of his first year in office. He discusses such topics as: economic policy and development, budgeting, bringing back jobs, and the Governor's plans for the following year to focus on education and environmental protection.)
          - [Side 2], 12/12/1983; [9940-SR-92-2]; (Governor Blanchard's interview with the Detroit News. In the interview Blanchard reflects on some of the accomplishments of his first year in office. He discusses such topics as: economic policy and development, budgeting, bringing back jobs, and the Governor's plans for the following year to focus on education and environmental protection.)
        - Interview with Larry Lea, [9940-SR-93]; 1 audiocassettes (Audiocassettes) (Box 196)
          - [Side 1; no side 2], 12/19/1983; [9940-SR-93-1]; (James Blanchard interview with Larry Lea, discussing his first year as Govenor of Michigan. Govenor Blanchard discusses the issues that he faced during the first year in office, including the state's financial crisis, and economic development. Govenor Blanchard also discusses some of the issues he faced, including the hostility between legislative powers and the lack of cooperation to improve Michigan's future. He expresses some of the projects he hopes to address in the following year, such as education and the economic development program.)
        - 1983 review, [9940-SR-94]; 1 audiocassettes (Audiocassettes) (Box 196)
          - [Side 1; no side 2], 12/19/1983; [9940-SR-94-1]; (MNN broadcasts with Governor Blanchard, discussing the review of his first year in office. Govenor Blanchard addresses some of the successful programs from his first year as govenor, including the new economic development policy, the fiscal recovery program, and the 20 point program to help bring back jobs to Michigan. Another broadcast recorded from Govenor Blanchard described the more personal aspects of what it was like to be Govenor, including some of his greatest accomplishments and regrets from his first year, and how his life has changed as Govenor. In the third broadcast Govenor Blanchard discusses his family's Christmas traditions.)
        - Speech to Roadbuilders; Michigan Press Association Speech, [9940-SR-110]; 1 audiocassettes (Audiocassettes) (Box 196)
          - [Side 1] Speech to Roadbuilders, 1985 January 18; 1985 January 25; [9940-SR-110-1]; (A speech to Michigan roadbuilders on the government's plan to fix and maintain the state's roads on January 18, 1985.)
            (Duration: 00:08:25)
          - [Side 2] Michigan Press Association Speech, 1985 January 18; 1985 January 25; [9940-SR-110-2]; (A speech at Michigan Press Association by Governor Blanchard about the 1985 Michigan State of the State Address.)
            (Duration: 00:42:42)
        - Governor's Report, [9940-SR-111]; 1 audiocassettes (Audiocassettes) (Box 196)
          - [Side 1; no side 2], 1985 January 24; [9940-SR-111-1]; (Interview of Governor Blanchard for the Governor's Report series. Topic discussed include the 1985 Michigan State of the State Address.)
            (Duration: 00:28:29)
        - Budget Briefing, [9940-SR-112]; 1 audiocassettes (Audiocassettes) (Box 196)
          - [Side 1], 1985 January 29; [9940-SR-112-1]; (The Governor introducing the 1985-1986 fiscal year budget for the state of Michigan to the Joint Committee. The Budget Director, Robert Naftaly, and others presented a slide show explaining the proposed budget.)
            (Duration: 00:46:18)
          - [Side 2], 1985 January 29; [9940-SR-112-2]; (The continuation of the budget proposal presentation. Near 06:30, the tape switches to the post presentation question and answer session with the Michigan Joint Committee.)
            (Duration: 00:27:05)
        - Bob Naftaly, [9940-SR-113]; 1 audiocassettes (Audiocassettes) (Box 196)
          - [Side 1], 1985 February 1; [9940-SR-113-1]; (The Budget Director, Robert Naftaly, explaining the 1985-1986 fiscal year budget.)
            (Duration: 00:16:11)
        - Public Health Directors' Conference Speech; Fred Douglas, [9940-SR-114]; 1 audiocassettes (Audiocassettes) (Box 196)
          - [Side 1], February 6, 1985; [9940-SR-114-1]; (Public Health Directors' Conference: Introduction; James Blachard's speech on Michigan Government and healthcare; discussion on environmental protection as prevention.)
            (Duration: 00:09:35)